<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on This Coding Life</title>
    <link>http://andrealmar.com/categories/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on This Coding Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>andre@y7mail.com (André Almar)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andre@y7mail.com (André Almar)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2016 Andre Almar, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 20:53:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andrealmar.com/categories/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Author</title>
      <link>http://andrealmar.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 20:53:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <author>andre@y7mail.com (André Almar)</author>
      <guid>http://andrealmar.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;whoami&#34;&gt;$ whoami:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi. My full name is Andre Almeida Araujo. But you can call me &lt;code&gt;Andre Almar&lt;/code&gt;. ALMAR stands for “&lt;strong&gt;ALM&lt;/strong&gt;eida &lt;strong&gt;AR&lt;/strong&gt;aujo”, Got it?
I’m the founder of this blog and a software engineer passionate about programming languages, operating systems, platforms and distributed systems and I&amp;rsquo;m always open and eager to learn. Most of the posts you will see here are based on things I have experienced myself or I was just curious to read, learn and write about. In this blog I do my best to share my musings about the Software Development world. I have a motto: &amp;ldquo;My goal is to achieve excellence in everything I&amp;rsquo;m doing&amp;rdquo;. Oh&amp;hellip;and if you have a good challenge for me, drop me a message and I will be glad to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-became-who-i-am&#34;&gt;How I became Who I am:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was born in 1985 in a small town of the Minas Gerais state in Brazil. One day my father came home with a beige box, a monitor, a keyboard and a mice. My father used that box to write texts and print them in his Epson LX810 printer. I became curious about how that big box works and started to learn how to deal with that. Then I&amp;rsquo;ve found inside that PC a game called Actua Soccer. I was mesmerized. That beige box became my first source of fun the whole day. I used to spent hours and hours just playing that game.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In summer 2002 I started to study Data Processing. In my free time I helped some customers and friends on the development of their websites, so I learned CSS and HTML in order to do that. I made a lot of websites using MS Frontpage. In 2006 I moved to Belo Horizonte (where I currently live) to study Information Technology in a local University. In my course I was exposed to C++, Java and other technologies. But then I saw Python. I fell in love with the language and its simplicity. It was love at a first sight ;)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
After I got my diploma in 2011, I left university to work for several companies doing consulting work in various customers. From government to construction companies I worked with many customers around Latin America. But I was working with enterprise software and I was not feeling the fun anymore. Then I decided to focus more on Python.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I still do consulting work and rebranded my company &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pydevv.com&#34;&gt;PyDevv&lt;/a&gt; to focus more on what I want to do for living which is Python (and its related technologies) full-time.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
After a little sabbatical I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a new gig &lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Hi! I&amp;#39;m a software developer and after a little sabbatical I&amp;#39;m looking for a new job! Who&amp;#39;s hiring? email: andre@y7mail.com  💖 thanks!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Andre Almar (@andre_almar) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/andre_almar/status/694169305097854976&#34;&gt;February 1, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; so if you have something in mind that is good for both of us please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:andre@y7mail.com&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; !!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-can-download-my-cv-here-pdf&#34;&gt;You can download my CV here (PDF):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../download/andre-araujo-cv.pdf&#34;&gt;Resumé&lt;/a&gt; - last updated Aug 26, 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;featured-in&#34;&gt;Featured in:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/issue-archive/2015/15-may/o35architect-2541586.html&#34;&gt;Oracle Magazine&lt;/a&gt; - Architect – Get Where You’re Going&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../images/hoje_em_dia_newspaper.jpeg&#34;&gt;Hoje em Dia newspaper&lt;/a&gt; - Software contabiliza emissões de carbono (news about my old startup).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>